Uh just knowing that this off season
would you would be potentially looking
at quarterbacks in this class. Did that
impacted all the front offic's approach
to evaluating this class and this this
draft?
>> Uh yeah, I would say it didn't really
impact our approach. We always kind of
do our due diligence in the class, but
we probably spend a little more extra
time on it. Um it's always a
collaborative process. with our area
scouts, you know, to our kind of over
the top scouts to, you know, less and
less and getting the coaches involved in
the spring. So, it didn't really change
our process. Um, but it was definitely
something that we were focused on. Um,
and we knew we had to address, but um,
our process stays the same and try to
stay true to that. So,
>> what was the pre-draft process like with
Ty?
>> Yeah. Um, it really started, I mean,
credit to Les, he really does some due
diligence on quarterbacks. Probably
starting over the summer when he was at
the Manning Passing Academy and
evaluating all those guys there. And
then once we got to a point where you
kind of identified Tai as somebody who
would uh work well with Shawn and Bit,
what we're looking for at that position,
evolved from there, but um really a a
year-long process starting in July. What
was it that made you believe he would
work well with Sean?
>> You have to be smart to flagger. Uh you
can tell just watching the film that
like he knows how to play the position.
Um super smart quarterback. Obviously
grew up with a dad as a coach. So he has
lived and breathed it for his entire
life and um there are it's a it's a rare
trade of the guy who has played by year
ring of college football to to find
that. So that was something that stood
up to us. How concerning if at all was
the fact that he had only played 15
games?
>> I wouldn't say it was something we were
overly concerned about. Um obviously had
spent the time in Alabama there um
learning um he was at a you know high
level program and then we were able to
evaluate all the types of throws. Um he
was at a lot of big moments. So, we felt
like there was enough in that sample
size where we didn't have any pause
about the starts and now it's something
that a lot of people uh weigh
differently, but for us that wasn't a
big u wasn't a big hold up um and
something we felt confident on. We felt
confident based on what he had put on
tape that he was uh the right guy. You
know,
>> Nicole, I know you do a lot with
analytics. How much did that play into
um you know, the evaluation of Tai um
not just in terms of his game, but where
he you know would need to be selected?
Uh, good question. I think I wish that I
could tell you that we had really high
level analytics on where guys are going
to go. We're all kind of holding on to
our scene at that point. Was hoping that
he doesn't. So, uh, nothing really
there. Um, in terms of the evaluation, I
mean, we have so many different, uh,
metrics across the board for all
positions quarterback included in DAR.
So, uh, absolutely pay a role. Nicole,
what did the collaboration process like
working with Lesne and and Sean McBay?
>> That is a great question. Uh
the entire process, the cool thing about
being here, I've never been anywhere
else, but um it's an extremely
collaborative process and I feel very
lucky to be working in a group where
there is such communion between the
coaching side and the scouting side. Uh
it doesn't feel like work. I think
Glenn's kind of alluded to our draft
meetings that his office maybe
yesterday, but with me, John, other
members of our scouting staff have Sean
Le, it's uh it's a very fine environment
that we go through this process and we
probably align that when we get to the
end. But now we go back to coaching uh
kind of on their side, scouting on our
side, but it's one of the most fun
things about this time of year is going
to work so collaboratively with both of
them. I know the draft is usually about
planning for the future already, but uh
was that more so the case this year with
the approach to this year's class,
especially given the amount of
continuity this roster already had?
>> Yeah, I would definitely say that's
something we're always taking into
account. And I think when you look at
our um free agents coming up after this
upcoming season, uh there was something
we really wanted to be able to plan for
obviously because it's a high number of
guys, high number high number of high
level contributors. So, um, having guys
with, uh, you know, secession plans in
place, uh, really helps. And our, we're
fortunate where our roster is in a place
where we felt like we didn't have a ton
of glic needs. Um, we're able to take
guys that we really felt confident in
being contributors right away, but also,
you know, be starters three, four years
down the line, you know, two years down
the line, whatever it may be. But, um,
that was definitely something we thought
about a lot in all the guys we selected.
So, we're happy with how that turned
out.
>> Okay. Go ahead. You guys mentioned Kai's
intelligence. Was there a moment or I
guess situation you saw in men that made
that stand out to you guys?
>> Uh I would say and it's maybe not maybe
not be an intelligent way but the one
game that I always go back to is you
watch him play against Auburn this year
where things were really messy. Um he
was under a lot of pressure up front. Um
and things were really just moving fast
and it's not his best statistical game.
It's not a game where he stands up. you
see um in some of the clutch moments um
him being able to rise up uh make plays
to get them you know to get them a big
win. That was a game that really like
stood out because it's not the game that
game that everybody talks about. I think
he only threw for like 130 yards but
when you watch that game and you know
really evaluate the tape you're like
holy cow that's incredible across the
line. So um that's a game that always
like stands out to me. I think from an
intelligence standpoint, you see it on
tape every play he puts on our tape.
Like you see him process, be able to
read one, two to three, hitting backside
throws, things that we um have a big
appreciation for in our offense. So I
think that stands out over the course of
the season long tape, but that Auburn
game specifically is one that I've
always hung on. I was like, "Wow, that
is that is a really cool performance
that nobody is probably going to ever
talk about." Part of the collaborative
process, as it's been described before
here, is not necessarily having yes men
and yes women on a staff. You having
people that will give strong opinions
that don't necessarily align with, you
know, maybe less or or Shawn. So, was
there any push back? Was there what was
the debate about the Simpson using that
pick for Simpson? Was it was everyone on
board from the get-go? Yes, this is it.
or were there was there discussion
saying no maybe we need someone that's
going to help us immediately?
>> Uh I would say there wasn't there wasn't
a ton of push back on this one and that
was that would when you're you know
selecting a quarterback you want um you
obviously want there to be good
discussion but it it's it's tough to
pick a quarterback and have one that
everybody u feels good about and strong
about. And I think Tai was that for us.
And um the proc process really brought
that to life. Whether it be our scouts
doing all their evaluations um and how
strong they felt about Tai. And then um
you know when we did our evaluations
less um getting the coaches involved
there was there was really collective
buyin. And so um that made it you know
kind of be like a no-brainer for us
where we were we were able to um select
him at 13. So I think that's that's a
unique thing though. It's it doesn't
always work like that with with really
any player, but it it spoke to Tai and
how um strong we felt like the fit was
for the Rams.
>> But it is fairly unique to draft a
player in the first round top 15 and not
really know when, you know, he will have
that chance to get on the field. So, how
did you guys just kind of rationalize
with understanding this pick could, you
know, it could be a year, it could be
two years, could be three years and and
finding out where to value him. I think
it's what I alluded to earlier. Uh
particularly for Shawn and the way that
we like to play, you can't just plug and
play quarterback in there and when you
find somebody that you think uh fits
that system and has the buy in from
everybody at the building that we found.
I don't think it really matters when you
take them, you just take them and maybe
two years, three years, four years, who
knows? But it's it's a hard thing to
find. So when you find it, you you pick.
What traits of his made you feel like he
was the right fit for the system?
Specifically,
>> uh things we alluded to, his
intelligence, um you watched him play in
a pro style system. He makes a lot of
pro style throws and caring and
translation.
>> Nicole, understanding after last season
that tight end sets were going to be a
part of this offense moving forward,
like what how if at all did that impact
the way you evaluated tight ends in this
class? a ton. Um, also value or impacted
the fact that we took one today. Um,
the interesting thing with that is that
the move to 13 personnel kind of Khan
organically. Um,
you saw someone told us earlier was that
the most tight ends taken in the second
wrap that today on day two.
>> Um, which is fascinating and it'll be
interesting to see how the league
evolves from there. Um, but a ton and
and I think part of that too is because
you're when you're playing with multiple
tight ends, you're uh have opportunities
to activate them in past situations that
are different than when you're playing
an 11. So that goes into the evaluation
with Max specifically. You saw him play
in different personnel gripants when he
was at Purdue versus Ohio State. So to
get to watch him across multiple years
um gave us a lot of insight into how he
would perform in various personnel
groupings of our team things like that.
So absolutely adding back.
>> I think one position just most a lot of
people expected to see maybe a little
earlier was wide receiver. So just how
do you feel about kind of how that
played out in the draft and then what
kind of led you to CJ Daniels?
>> Uh CJ was a guy we felt good about um
and felt like was a good strong fit
throughout the process. Um he's somebody
we got eyes early on in the fall um and
really followed and had appreciation for
throughout the process. Um so when he
started to fall today, it became a you
know we moved up I think 10 spots to
pick him. Um but he fits a lot of things
we're looking for in the offense. He he
runs routes at high level. He got great
feel for the game. He's got a big catch
rate. He has strong hands. Um so for us
it was a it was a great fit and we felt
like he was one of the last ones still
available that could really, you know,
impact our team this year and moving
forward. Um, so it was a it was a good
one. I know obviously there was a lot
of, you know, thought we did and we
discussed taking ones earlier, but just
the way that the board fell, we felt
really good about um the three guys were
able to add before him and then add CJ
today. That that that was strong group.
It was if you would have asked me on
Monday if that was how it played out, I
would have been very happy. So,
>> you didn't think you were going to leave
me dropped, but it was a lot of time to
sp.
>> I will say just to shout out one of our
scouts, uh, Anthony Robinson, I can't
remember when the meeting was. It was
probably, it might have been September,
maybe October. Uh, probably only thing
he said about CAD Daniels was, "This kid
is a Ram. Here we are." So, pretty cool
for us to start there and end up here.
>> Three years ago, you guys drafted 14
players. This year, you drafted five.
Last year, you drafted six. Which of
those do you prefer and what's the
pluses and minuses in terms of volume?
>> Yeah, I would say it's all about where
you're at in your team build and where
you feel like the depth of your roster
is. I think at the time we were um when
we had a large number of picks, our
roster was, you know, a little bit
thinner. I think when one breath we came
into the draft with like 45 guys on the
roster or something. So, we we needed
all the picks and all the college free
we could add. So, I think at that point
it was it was a real asset for us to
have that many picks. I think where
we're at now, um, you're always trying
to find guys like we're, especially in
day three, you're saying, "What is our
vision for this guy? How does he how's
he going to make our team?" Cuz it's not
going to be an easy team to make this
off season. So, for us, having a fewer
number of picks and guys we really, you
know, believe in was was um, was a good
thing for us, but I think it all depends
on where you're at, your team build, but
we felt like we're um, you know, a very
deep roster right now. So having a large
number of picks where we might be
drafting as we don't specifically have a
vision for is a challenge. So we're
we're happy with where it's at.
Obviously five I think is the lowest
we've ever had probably before. Um but
but it's not necessarily a bad thing for
we feel really good about the fun that
we ended up with. So
>> draft was heavy on offensive players.
Was that position coming into the
weekend or just how it played out?
>> How play out and you obviously consider
need various picks but I think
particularly with the Going in with
seven and then end up with five kind of
we're really picky best available since
that's the best player for our tune.
Seth not the intention just how it
worked out.
>> What's your favorite meal?
>> Yeah, you can pick yours up thinking
>> the one that just popped into my head
which is not my favorite but is now I'm
going to say it wrong. What has he been
saying to hold her up? The C.
>> Yeah. He says
>> I've heard that so many times.
>> That was going to be mine.
>> I'm not going to come up with a better
one than that. Right now,
>> yeah, it's from
>> killer.
>> I don't know if I can think of one off
the top. He's got so many that it's uh
>> it's funny being around him. He always
he knows everyone's name, but he acts
like he doesn't know everyone's name.
So, intentionally kind of mess up their
last name when they were talking about
players. And I'm like, I know you know
what it did. It just it's a funny quirk
that he was like, and I remember last
year when we drafted Josiah one one day
out of nowhere, he said like Josiah
Stewart and I was like, how do you why
didn't you just say his name right? He's
like, I've been practicing that one in
the shower.
>> I was like, I know I know we thought you
were
he likes a player if he knows first
name, last name, instead of
>> Oh, yeah.